<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | NJU Seismology</title>
    <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://huihuiweng.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viscoelastic ruptures</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/viscoelastic_ruptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/viscoelastic_ruptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classical theories using linear elasticity predict that crack propagation is bounded by a limiting speed, beyond which the energy balance becomes unphysical. Recent experiments in viscoelastic materials demonstrated that both tensile and frictional crack propagation can exceed classical speed limits.
However, the fundamental physics governing unbounded rupture speeds are still unclear.
Numerical simulations show that frictional ruptures in viscoelasticity can propagate at a continuum of terminal speeds that are not bounded by the classical speed limit.
All simulated rupture speeds are predicted by the newly developed theory of fracture mechanics incorporating viscoelasticity via the principle of energy balance.
In addition to the ratio of the fracture energy to the static energy release rate that can be used to uniquely predict the rupture propagation in linear elasticity, the scales of characteristic lengths in viscoelasticity also govern the energy balance.
Beyond the classical speed limit, the energy balance becomes independent of any macroscopic length and is controlled only by the local properties around the rupture tip.
These numerical and theoretical findings fundamentally advance our understanding of dynamic rupture propagation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow and fast earthquakes</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/slow_and_fast_eqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/slow_and_fast_eqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular earthquakes suddenly release elastic energy accumulated underground and radiate strong seismic waves, while slow earthquakes (&amp;ldquo;slow slip events&amp;rdquo;) act silently without detectable seismic waves. Because slow slip events occur worldwide and could trigger devastating earthquakes, geophysicists are particularly interested in understanding their fundamental mechanics and their relationship with the fast, damaging earthquakes. A yet unsolved piece of the puzzle is the empirical relation between the magnitude and duration of both types of earthquakes: it is still debated whether or not this relation is similar for slow slip events and regular earthquakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that both slow and fast earthquakes can be understood by a new theory of dynamic fracture mechanics. This theory accounts for an essential ingredient that was missing in previous models and experiments, the “finite seismogenic depth”: the portion of the fault that slides during a large event has a limited depth extent, shorter than its horizontal length. The predictions of the new model are supported by validations against earthquake simulations and observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work provides insight on how earthquakes can develop a broad spectrum of rupture speeds, from arbitrarily slow ones to seismic wave speeds.  In particular, the new model shows how earthquake rupture speed is controlled by a non-dimensional number arising from energy balance: the ratio between the available elastic energy and the energy dissipated by fault slip. The model also reconciles the debated observations of the relation between magnitude and duration of slow slip events. It explains how this relation can be similar to that of regular earthquakes when focusing on events from a single region, but radically different when combining observations from multiple regions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supershear ruptures</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/supershear_eqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/supershear_eqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the most damaging natural hazards, earthquakes are still today one of the least understood phenomena in Earth Sciences. Earthquakes happen when rocks on either side of a tectonic fault slide. The sliding, however, does not occur along the whole fault at once but starts at one point, the
hypocenter, and then spreads over the entire fault at a speed known as the &amp;ldquo;rupture speed&amp;rdquo; of the earthquake. Geophysicists are particularly interested in rupture speeds because the faster they are, the stronger the seismic waves and therefore the greater the damage caused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seismic models developed so far concluded that earthquakes could not propagate in a stable and sustainable way at arbitrary speeds. Scientists had therefore determined a forbidden speed   range situated between the speed of P and S waves, the two main seismic waves that propagate through the Earth. However, progress in the seismological observation of earthquakes has made it possible to demonstrate that recent earthquakes had actually propagated within the forbidden range. Such was the case for the 2018 earthquake in Palu, Indonesia, for example, which caused a destructive tsunami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to overcome two crucial limitations of the previous models. The first was to rely on 2-dimensional models, while the Earth is 3-dimensional. The second was to assume either a horizontal or a vertical direction of sliding, while earthquake sliding can be oblique. By overcoming these two limitations, they were able to explain why the &amp;ldquo;forbidden speeds&amp;rdquo; are actually admissible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New 3D rupture theory</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/equation-of-motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/equation-of-motion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of ruptures in 3-D dynamic rupture simulations can be well described by the following inertial equation-of-motion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$F(G_c/G_0) = M(v_r) \cdot \dot{v}_r$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $G_c$ is the fracture energy, $G_0$ is the static energy release rate, $v_r$ is the ruptuer speed, $\dot{v}_r$ is the rupture acceleration, $F()$ and $M()$ are the known &amp;ldquo;Force&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mass&amp;rdquo; terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic rupture simulation for the 2015 Mw7.8 Nepal earthquake</title>
      <link>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/dynamic_rupture_simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://huihuiweng.github.io/en/project/dynamic_rupture_simulations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By utilizing different trade-off patterns of source parameters and multiple observations for the first time, we can determine the frictional parameters of the seismogenic fault. The best fit dynamic model yields a Dc (slip-weakening distance) value of ~0.6 m, in contrast to the previous kinematical estimation of ~5 m.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
